老妈  淡定
Ma, Ma, calm down.
听我说
Listen to me.
我知道上面说着用鼠标点击
I know it says click with the mouse,
但在笔记本电脑上  触控板就相当于鼠标了
but on a laptop, the trackpad is the mouse.
现在  把你的手指放上去
Now, put your finger on it.
无所谓用哪根手指
Doesn't matter which finger.
明智的选择
Good choice.
现在把指针移到电子邮件图标上
Now move it down to your e-mail icon.
对  就是那个小信封图标
Yeah, the little envelope.
什么叫"它长什么样"
What do you mean, "What does it look like?"
它当然长个信封样!
It looks like an envelope!
行啊  你要是不喜欢电脑
Fine, you don't like the computer,
那就别用了
don't use it!
行啊  我们可以换个沙拉搅拌机  再见
Sure, we can exchange it for a salad spinner. Good-bye!
这就是你一直后悔买的那个光明节礼物吧
That's a Hanukkah present you're regretting, huh?
光明节:犹太民族最隆重的节日
我不能说所有无法掌握当代技术的
I won't say that all senior citizens
老年人就应该被当众鞭策一番
who can't master technology should be publicly flogged,
但倘若我们拿一两位作为案例
but if we made an example of one or two,
或许能更好的鞭策他人努力学习呢
it might give the others incentive to try harder.
我有个好主意
I had a great idea.
我们总会被迫停下工作
You know how we're always having
去解某些微分方程式吧
to stop and solve differential equations,
比如你做傅里叶分析的时候
like when you're doing Fourier analysis,
或是用到薛定谔方程的时候
or using the Schr dinger equation?
霍华德用不到那个  他只不过是个工程师
Howard doesn't. He's only an engineer.
我一直在想其实我们可以写个小程序
I was thinking, we could write a little app
通过使用手写识别技术
that would use handwriting recognition,
然后通过一个符号运算引擎来计算
and then run it through a symbolic evaluation engine.
这样  只要你使用你的智能手机
You just use your smartphone,
把你的方程式拍出来后就迎刃而解了
take a picture of the equation and bam!
你们知道什么应用程序算牛吗  能制造放屁声的程序
You know what's a great app? The one that makes fart noises.
知道吗  莱纳德
You know, Leonard,
那的确是个可行的主意
that's actually a valid idea.
真的不错哦
Very good.
你的口吻能否别弄得像是"我是一只刚学会
Can you say that and not make it sound like I'm a cat
如何上厕所的猫"似的
who learned how to use the toilet?
不行
No.
两项成就都让人感到啧啧称奇
The two achievements are equally surprising
同样令人钦佩
and equally admirable,
但如果要选的话
though if pressed,
我不得不说那只猫的成就更胜一筹
I'd have to give a slight edge to the cat.
我还是拯救你于水火之中
I'll save you the pain and nervousness
给你一个你期待已久的答案吧
of waiting for the answer.
我同意参与你的计划  恭喜你
I agree to be part of your project. Congratulations.
我的荣幸啊
Oh, yay for me.
你们怎么说
What about you guys?
我不敢保证什么
I can't promise anything,
但有人就用这种东西赚到过钱呢
but people do make money off stuff like this.
能赚点外快也是不错的选择
A few extra bucks would be nice.
我终于能从我妈家搬出去了
I could finally move out of my mother's house.
你搬到哪去呢
Where would you go?
我一直梦想着能在车库上面
I always dreamed about
搭造起属于自己的小天地
building a little place of my own over the garage
如果我挣到更多的钱  我就能从工作中抽身
You know, if I made more money, I could take time off from work
带着美女来一趟潜艇之旅了
and give pretty girls submarine rides.
那是什么玩意
What's that?
某种诡异的性爱方式吗
Some weird sex thing?
不是啊
No.
就是你带着美女坐在你的
You take pretty girls underwater
私人潜艇里  让她们欣赏鱼儿
in your private submarine, and you show them fish.
为什么所有事到你这都要龌龊一下
Why does everything have to be dirty with you?
我想我们可以在晚上一起做这个
I was thinking we could work on this at night,
也许经过几周的努力后
and then maybe in a couple of weeks,
就能有我们自己的应用程序贩售了
we'll have ourselves an app to sell.
我们这听起来像是在做生意啊
Sounds like we're in business.
我认为我们应该拍一张  留住这精彩的瞬间
I think we should take a picture to capture this moment.
-好啊  -哦
- Yeah. - Oh!
你们说  这是不是我99美分花的最值的一次
Was that the best 99 cents I ever spent, or what?
生活大爆炸第四季第十二集
我查过应用商店了
I checked the App Store.
应用商店:苹果公司为应用程序设计的下载平台
还没人做过
No one is doing
手写识别解微分方程的应用程序呢
handwriting-recognition differential equation solving.
天呐  你小声点
Oh, dear Lord, shush.
为什么
What?
你好不容易能有个好点子  莱纳德
You have so few good ideas, Leonard.
你打算就这么轻易地把它
And you're just going to spill the beans
当着一个外人的面泄露出去吗
in front of an outsider?
说谁呢  我吗
Who, me?
谢尔顿  我不觉得佩妮
Sheldon, I don't think Penny cares
多在乎这个基于手写识别技术的微分...
about handwriting-recognition based differential...
*夜晚的星星大而亮呀*
*The stars at night are big and bright*
*深深地埋藏在德州的中央*
*Deep in the heart of Texas*
她不会来盗取我们的点子
She's not going to steal our idea.
-什么点子  -我们要写一个应用程序...
- What idea? - We're gonna write an application...
*草原的星空宽而高呀*
*The prairie sky is wide and high*
*深深地埋藏在...*
*Deep in the heart...*
行了  别唱了
Okay, stop, stop!
*德州的中央*
*Of Texas*
无论你们的秘密是什么
Whatever your secret is,
我确信它必定无聊至极  所以我不会有兴趣的
I'm sure it's boring, so I'm not interested.
一点也不无聊啊
It's not boring at all.
你想想  在高阶数学中
You see, in higher order mathematics,
一定会有
there are certain sets
-联立方程组  它们有时...  -无聊
- of equations that... - Bored.
满意了吗
Satisfied?
恐怕很难
Hardly.
试想一下这个不太可能却又非常真实的情节吧
Consider this unlikely but very plausible scenario.
一位年轻女子只身来到大都市
A young woman alone in the big city.
她荒谬的演员梦想
Her ridiculous dream
欺骗了她  从而深深地打击了她
of becoming an actress lies shattered about her.
拜托  你停一下好吗
Hey, wait a minute.
等等  我们看看他的后续如何
Well, hang on. Let's see where he's going.
然后现实打击了她
Then it hits her.
她如何才能生存下去呢
How is she going to survive?
因为她胸无大志且身无长物
I mean, she has no prospects, no marketable skills.
直到有一天
And then one day,
她遇到了一群天才们
she meets a group of geniuses
以及天才们的朋友霍华德
and their friend Howard.
我...
Hey, I...
你也等等  我们看看他的后续如何
Hang on. Let's see where he's going.
她与这帮人交朋友  然后伺机等候
She befriends them, and then lies in wait
直到这帮人有了一个可销售的点子
until they reveal a marketable idea,
于是她盗取了点子  卖给了出价最高的人
which she steals and sells to the highest bidder.
-这也太扯了  -哦  是吗
- That is ridiculous. - Oh, is it?
那你倒是给我们个合理的解释
Let's see you come up with an explanation
为何这个女人一直跟我们厮混在一起
as to why this woman hangs out with us all the time.
太棒了  你们知道吗
Oh, great. You know what?
我已经从你们这蹭到晚饭了
I've already mooched dinner off you guys.
所以我不需要再听这个点子了
I don't need to listen to this.
这就是你要的答案  免费食物
There's your answer-- free food.
好吧  我已经自作主张
All right, I've taken the liberty
起草了这些工作流程图
of drafting these workflow charts
这里列出了我们形形色色的职务以及
which outline our various duties and the path we will follow
开发这独创程序过程中需遵照的事项
as we develop our ground-breaking new app.
为何我负责的是电话服务
Hey, why am I in charge of phone support?
貌似有点种族主义
Seems a bit racist.
一个操着印度口音的客服
A customer service representative
能够给客人们留下一种
with an Indian accent will create the impression
我们这是跨国公司  使用海外客服中心的印象
we're a vast enterprise that uses overseas call centers.
哦
Oh.
很聪明
Very clever.
但还是有种族色彩
But still racist.
提醒下  你叫史蒂夫来自威奇托[美国城市]
Duly noted, Steve from Wichita.
为什么我被列为你的行政助理
Why am I listed as your executive assistant?
因为"秘书"这个词已经变得不大光彩了
Because the word "Secretary" has fallen into disrepute.
提醒下  我妈妈的生日快到了
FYI, my mother's birthday is coming up.
我需要你来帮我挑选个礼物
I'm going to need you to pick up a present.
好吧  我们需要暂时先停一下了
Okay, we need to stop for a minute.
莱纳德  拜托  我们可以在休憩时再谈
Leonard, please, we can talk during our break.
这个午夜马上就有事情要做了
We have one coming up at midnight.
我们需要小吃
We'll need snacks.
谢尔顿  这个并不是你负责的
Sheldon, you're not in charge.
这是我的点子  我才是负责的
It's my idea. I'm in charge.
当然是你负责啊
Oh, of course you are.
快看看上面的组织机构吧
Look at the organizational chart.
你被清楚地列为了奠基人
You're clearly listed as founder.
是啊  同时你被列为了首席执行官
Well, yes, and you're listed as Chief Executive Officer,
首席财务官和首席运营官
Chief Financial Officer and Chief Operating Officer.
你还少说了首席科技官
You missed Chief Science Officer,
董事局主席以及秘密圣诞委员会首脑
Chairman of the Board, and Head of the Secret Santa Committee.
好了
Okay.
你现在就需要搞明白这件事
You need to get clear on this right now.
我才是这个计划的决策人
I am in charge of this project.
哦哦  莱纳德想取代谢尔顿成为"书呆子"界的领袖喽
Ooh. Leonard's going all alpha nerd on Sheldon's ass...
好吧  好吧  我不打算跟你争执下去了
All right. All right, I'm not going to argue with you.
谢尔顿·库珀如果不团队协作也一事无成
Sheldon Cooper is nothing if not a team player.
霍夫斯塔德博士  一切由你指挥
Dr. Hofstadter, you have the conn.
谢谢
Thank you.
我认为我们可以先从用户界面开始讨论
I thought we might start by talking about the user interface.
哦天呐  我们失败定了
Oh, dear Lord, we're doomed.
那么这个按钮
So this button here
能让你扫描一个新方程
will allow you to scan a new equation,
而你按这边的按钮
but over here, you can press this,
就能替换新的系数
and just substitute new values for the coefficients.
不错哎  头儿
Good one, boss.
啥
What?
这个图例
This diagram.
你以为您是想讲个开场笑话
I assume you were opening with a joke.
毫无疑问鼓舞了我这个小员工的团队精神
It certainly buoyed up this employee's esprit de corps.
这不是玩笑  就是这么设计
It's not a joke. It's the real design.
这样的话  能让我稍微修改27处
In that case, may I offer 27 little tweaks
让这玩意儿看着不那么丢人吗
to make it slightly less embarrassing?
谢尔顿  我觉得这个能成
Sheldon, I think this will work.
就按我说的做先
Let's just try it my way.
不好意思
Oh, I'm-I'm sorry.
我以为你希望你的属下
I assumed that you wanted
能畅所欲言  直言进谏
candid truth-telling from your employees,
而我现在意识到  你不过是喜欢
but I realize now, you want the mindless nattering
盲目奉承  沾沾自喜的应声虫
of complacent yes-men.
说完了吗
Are you done?
听你的  头儿
If you say so, boss.
好  按下这个键
So right now, this button-press event
就能调用一个虚拟程序...
is just triggering a dummy procedure call...
应用程序叫这名儿怎样
How about this for the app name?
出奇-好用-微分-方程-相关
The Surprisingly Helpful Equation-Linked
优化-计算器
Differential Optimized Numerator.
首字母连起来就是"谢尔顿"
So it spells "Sheldon."
是吗
Does it?
好巧啊
A happy accident.
现在不急着起名  霍华德  来吧
We're not doing names now. Howard?
我也说了  现在只是个虚拟程序
Like I was saying, right now it's just a dummy procedure,
但最终会进入...
but eventually, it will drop us into...
好吧  如果我们先不起名
All right, fine. If we're not going to give it a name,
好歹起个秘密代号吧
can we at least give it a secret code designation?
-不要  -听我说完
- No. - Hear me out.
原子弹计划的代号是曼哈顿计划
The atomic bomb was The Manhattan Project.
Win95最早的代号是芝加哥计划
Windows 95 was originally Project Chicago.
而咱的应用程序  我低调建议就叫顿尔谢计划好了
For our app, I would humbly suggest Project Nodlehs.
不过是"谢尔顿"倒过来而已
That's just "Sheldon" Backwards.
又是个愉快的巧合啊
Another happy accident.
我们现在不浪费时间起名字
We're not wasting time with names right now.
我懂了
I see.
能公开讨论下这个决议吗
Is that decision open for discussion?
不
No.
能公开讨论下为什么不公开讨论吗
Is the decision to not discuss it open for discussion?
不
No.
再说一遍
Again,
现在这只是个虚拟程序
right now it's just a dummy procedure,
但最终会进入...
but eventually, it will drop us into...
我要对现在的领导人发起不信任投票
I call for a vote of no confidence
并且要求立即更换领导人
and an immediate change in leadership.
谢尔顿  快住口
Sheldon, stop it.
在人类活动过程中  有必要缓解
When in the course of human events, it becomes necessary
三位有能力的科学家的合作关系
to dissolve the bonds that tie three competent scientists together...
-够了  谢尔顿  -好吧  直接开始投票吧
- That's enough, Sheldon. - All right, let's get right to the vote.
现在请所有反对莱纳德
Show of hands-- all those opposed
和他的专制帝国的人  举手
to Leonard and his reign of tyranny.
够了  你被炒了
Okay, that's it, you're fired.
真的吗
Really?
为什么
Why?
因为你没法和人合作
Because you're impossible to work with.
我明白了
I see.
能公开讨论下吗
And is that open for discussion?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
早上好  大懒虫
Oh. Good morning, shoemaker.
我想你会很高兴看到
I think you'll be pleased
昨晚精灵们的辛勤劳动成果
with what the elves were up to last night.
我不是炒了你么
I fired you.
我知道  我现在是个合同工
Oh, I know. I'm now an independent contractor.
不  你啥都不是
No, you are now nothing.
你和这项目没有一毛钱关系了
You have no connection to this project whatsoever.
但我做了改进
But I made it better.
我不要你做改进  我要按我自己的来
I don't want it better. I want it my way.
这话真是意味深长  是吧
Well, that speaks volumes, doesn't it?
好吧  我想我还是去穿公车裤吧
All right, I suppose I'll go put on my bus pants.
公车裤是什么玩意
What the hell are bus pants?
就是穿在普通裤子外面的裤子
They are pants one wears over one's regular pants
因为你要坐在公车上
when one sits on bus seats
别人坐过的椅子上
that other people have previously sat on.
不过也许你是企业里
But perhaps from your lofty heights
高高在上的领导  恐怕不会理解
atop the corporate ladder, you've lost touch
身为普通人的辛酸苦辣
with the struggles of the common man.
听着  我还是很乐意开车送你去上班
Look, I'm still happy to drive you to work.
在这点上没有改变
Nothing's changed in that regard.
我们还是室友  还是朋友
We're still roommates, we're still friends.
但你却把我  你最好的朋友
Except you identified me, your best friend,
当成一块坏死的肉
as a gangrenous limb that needed to be severed
从组织上割下来再扔掉
from the organism and tossed away.
你这有严重拿破仑情结的小个子
The desperate act of a little man
还真是穷凶极恶
with a big Napoleon complex.
老子告诉你
You know what?
速度穿你的公交裤去吧
Go put on your bus pants.
昨天晚上  我做了个梦
Mm. Last night, I had a dream
我们因为这应用程序发了大财
we got so rich from the app,
我俩买了两幢相邻的别墅
you and I bought matching side-by-side mansions.
但是...
But...
中间有条秘密隧道
there was a secret tunnel
从你的前庭连到我的后院
connecting your front yard to my back yard.
你觉得这是啥意思
What do you think that means?
意思是我们玩完手球后  我在家洗澡
It means after we play handball, I'm showering at home.
早上好  霍华德好友
Good morning, Friend Howard.
拉杰好友
Friend Raj.
两位先生在喝饮料啊
I see you gentlemen are enjoying beverages.
也许这些能让它们喝起来更美味
Perhaps they would taste better out of these.
"世上最伟大的天文物理学家"
"World's Greatest Astrophysicist"?
不用谢我  你应得的
Don't thank me. You earned it.
"霍华德·沃罗威茨"
"Howard Wolowitz."
为啥不是"世上最伟大的工程师"
Why not "World's Greatest Engineer"?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我在做标签的时候是这么打过
I typed that into the label maker,
但实在按不下确认键
but I just couldn't press enter.
现在谈正事吧
Now down to business.
你们何不抛弃莱纳德
What would it take for you to abandon Leonard
加入竞争对手  我的公司
and join me in a rival company?
要是这两个马克杯还不够
Unless, of course, the mugs are sufficient,
不管怎样  欢迎你们入伙
in which case, welcome aboard.
我们不会抛弃莱纳德
We're not quitting on Leonard.
我明白  你们的忠诚值得赞扬
I understand. Your loyalty is admirable.
但如果我再增加筹码呢
But what if I were to up the ante?
你在说什么鬼
What are you talking about?
字母组合钥匙链
Monogrammed key chains
还配有内置激光
with a built-in laser pointer.
还是不吗
No?
那印有我们大学
How about can cozies
吉祥物的保温罩呢
emblazoned with our university mascot?
冲啊  海狸
Go, Beavers.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
好  我们试下这个
Okay, let's try this one.
"球面汉克尔函数"
"Spherical Hankel function."
稍等
Hold on.
有了
That's it!
中了
Eureka!
喂  我们不是说好"中了"的时候
Hey, we agreed when it was "Eureka" Time,
要一起说的吗
we were all gonna say it together.
好吧  那再一起说一次好了
Fine. Let's say it together.
不了  这个时机已经过了
No. The moment has passed.
你们好  先生们
Greetings, gentlemen.
你们的小项目咋样了
How goes your little project?
你是指  "莱沃帕里"计划吗
You mean, "Project Lenwoloppali"?
是你们名字的组合啊
Ah, a combination of all your names.
真聪明
Very clever.
为啥不是"库萨纳德威茨"呢
I assume "Koothranardowitz" Was taken?
我们在扫描方程  效果还不错
We're actually scanning equations and getting good results.
好吧  你们继续努力吧
Oh, well then, by all means, carry on.
我不想妨碍你们的进程
I wouldn't want to impede your progress.
霍华德  你解决了安装时间的问题了吗
Howard, did you solve the install time problem yet?
没有  这有点难应付
No. It's a little tricky.
我准备查下图书馆的查询系统...
I'm gonna try having it pick up the libraries dyn...
你在搞什么
What are you doing?!
在演奏特雷门琴
Playing the theremin.
不  我是说  你拿特雷门琴在搞什么
No. I mean, what are you doing with a theremin?
演奏啊
Playing it.
我第一次听到星际迷航原声主题乐时
I've loved the theremin from the first moment
就爱上了特雷门琴了
I heard the original Star Trek theme.
我实在是不忍心
And it's been killing me
把它一直扔在柜子里积灰
that it just sits in my closet, gathering dust.
谢尔顿  我们在工作
Sheldon! We're working here!
没关系
That's all right.
我在演奏特雷门琴时几乎听不到你们说话
I can barely hear you over my theremin.
这真有点不讲道理
Well, that was a little uncalled for.
不  这他妈的太讲道理了 我们需要安静
No, that was completely called for. We need quiet.
就是说你们的项目比我的重要咯
So, your project is more important than mine?
如果你的项目就是给我捣蛋  那就是
Well, seeing as your project is to sabotage my project, yes.
别拐弯抹角的  莱纳德
Don't beat around the bush, Leonard.
你要是容不下我
If you don't want me here,
说出来  我会走人的
just say the word, and I'll leave.
稍微拐弯抹角一点也没什么嘛
Could have beaten around the bush a little.
*没人知晓*
Nobody knows
*我曾经见的离乱*
The trouble I've seen
*没人理解  我的悲伤*
Nobody knows my sorrow ?
你干嘛呢
What you doing?
联络你的母星吗
Trying to contact your home planet?
我在练习特雷门琴
I'm practicing my theremin.
*没人知晓*
Nobody knows
*我曾经见的离乱*
The trouble I've seen
*荣耀啊  哈利路亚*
Glory, hallelujah.
什么事儿惹你不开心了吗  谢尔顿
Something got you down, there, Sheldon?
莱纳德把我从家轰出来了
Leonard kicked me out of my own apartment.
还有应用程序小组
And his app team.
亲爱的  真可怜
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
他今天还不肯开车带我上班
He wouldn't drive me to work today.
搞得我不得不穿公交裤
I had to wear my bus pants.
-是这样吗  -嗯
- Is that so? - Yes.
现在裤子还粘糊糊的
And they're still sticky.
估计得扔掉了
Probably going to have to throw them away.
听着  你才不需要莱纳德和他的程序
Hey, you don't need Leonard and his app.
你可以跟我研究出来一个嘛
You can make one with me.
和你吗
With you?
说真的  我有个超赞的点子
Seriously, I have a great idea for one.
比你搬来洛杉矶
Is it better than your idea to move to Los Angeles
成为一个名演员的点子还赞吗
and become a famous actress?
行了  听着
Okay, look...
当你看到某人脚上的鞋子  让你很感冒
when you see someone wearing shoes you like,
你就拍一张照片
you just snap a picture of them,
然后用这个程序直接在网上
and the app goes on the Internet
查到哪里有卖
to find out where you can buy them.
这就是你应用程序的点子
That's your app idea?
你不感兴趣吗
Well, you don't like it?
我刚才没这么说  不过  我确实不感兴趣
I didn't say that. But no, I don't.
为什么
Why not?
佩妮  让我从何说起啊
Oh, Penny, where do I begin?
超越了这个点子弱智程度的
The simple-mindedness of your idea
只有愚蠢的消费者至上主义和俗不可耐
is exceeded only by its crass consumerism and banality.
莱纳德不要跟你合作
And Leonard didn't want to work with you?
真"稀奇"啊
Imagine that.
我知道  确实匪夷所思啊
I know, it's baffling.
*没人知晓*
Nobody knows
*我曾经见的离乱*
The trouble I've seen...
谢尔顿  我要冲可可喝
Sheldon, I'm gonna make some cocoa.
你要喝吗
Do you want some?
你用什么冲  牛奶还是水
Do you make it with milk or water?
-牛奶  -货真价实的可可吗
- Milk. - Real cocoa?
包装上是这么说的
That's what it says on the packet.
你有那种小棉花糖吗
Do you have those little marshmallows?
没有  抱歉
No, sorry.
看来还真是配啊
Well, I suppose it's appropriate.
什么意思
What does that mean?
倒霉日喝烂饮料
A disappointing drink for a disappointing day.
喂  看这个
Hey, look at this.
学校里已经有二十个人登记了
20 people from the university have already signed up
咱的内测版
for our private beta.
我就说嘛
I'm telling you,
莱沃帕里微分方程扫描仪
the Lenwoloppali Differential Equation Scanner
满足了实际需求  咱要火了
meets a real need. We've got a hit.
你们觉得咱该定个什么价位
What do you think we should sell it for?
这个嘛  基于我们的潜在市场
Well, based on the fact that our potential market
大约七八十人的事实
is about 70 or 80 guys,
而你又想赚个潜水艇
and you want a submarine,
我的意见是一单一百万刀
I'd say about a million dollars a pop.
不如咱出个精简版  卖五十万
Well, what if we put out a lite version for half a million?
你懂吗  可以赚个口碑的说
You know, get the word of mouth going.
嗨  抱歉打扰了
Hi. I'm sorry to bother you guys,
你们得过来把你家谢尔顿领走
but you've got to come take your Sheldon back.
他怎么会在你家
What's he doing in your apartment?
他一人在大厅闷闷不乐  我就把他带回家了
Well, he was moping down in the lobby, so I invited him over.
现在我肠子都悔青了
Now I regret it.
他干啥让你后...废话一句  当我没说
Why do you regret... Uh, never mind, stupid question.
就不能带他一起玩儿到睡觉吗
Look, can't you just let him play with you until bedtime?
我们这不是玩儿
We're not playing.
这是正事
This is real work.
我们就要成为百-富翁咯
We're going to be hundred-aires.
成吧  要是我能让他道歉并且保证他乖呢
Okay. What if I got him to apologize and promise to behave?
这样的话  我们的研究组可以接受他
Then I guess we would let him back on the app team,
他回来之后  你说不定能坐着你的飞天猪仔
and while we're doing that, you could take an aerial tour
在空中游览洛城
of L.A. on your flying pig.
好吧  等着啊
Okay. Wait right here.
跟你们说吧  要是我有天发达了
I'll tell you one thing. If I get rich enough,
我就想带这样的女孩
that's the kind of girl I want to take
来一次潜水艇之旅
on a submarine ride.
而且没错  我是要龌龊一下
And yes, that time, I meant it to be dirty.
真的吗
Really?
莱纳德想让我回去吗
Leonard wants me back?
没错  他说你不在他们就群龙无首了
Oh, yes. He says they are lost without you.
这还用说
Well, we sure saw that coming.
那是
That's right.
你知道我准备干吗吗
You know what I'm going to do?
我准备就一直坐在这  由得他们去烦吧
I am going to sit here and just let them stew.
别  别  别
No, no, no. You know,
他们已经够受罪的了
they have suffered enough.
大家都够受罪的了
Everybody's suffered enough.
关键是  你得过去
The thing is, you're going to have to offer him
给他一个有面子的台阶下
a face-saving way out of this.
怎么给他台阶下
How?
道个歉呗
Say you're sorry.
不
Oh, no.
我亲爱的母亲玛丽·库珀太太可没教我撒谎
Mrs. Mary Cooper didn't raise her no liars.
好吧
Okay. Um...
那这样好不好  你不是一直想要学
How about this? You know how you're always trying
挖苦人吗
to learn about sarcasm?
-没有  -没有吗
- No.  - No?
我刚刚那就是挖苦
I was being sarcastic.
真不错
Oh. Good for you.
所以你只需要过去
So all you have to do here is say
跟莱纳德道歉
you're sorry to Leonard,
但是语气要带着挖苦
but say it sarcastically.
当然
Of course.
在他听来  那是我在示好
He will hear it as an attempt to mend fences,
但实际上咱俩清楚
as opposed to the withering condemnation
那是赤裸裸的谴责
you and I will know it to be.
没错  没错  我就这个意思
Yeah. Yeah, that was my plan.
好了  走吧  咱们过去
All right. Come on. Let's go.
顺便说一句  谢谢你
Oh, by the way, thank you
做了这么好喝的可可
for the delicious cocoa.
不客气
Oh, you're welcome.
我的挖苦功夫真是越来越精湛了
Boy, I'm getting good at this.
好吧  既然你归队了
Okay, now that you're back on the team,
那我们就给你介绍一下最新进展吧
let's get you caught up.
在你开始之前  我想再次
Before you begin, let me say again
为我之前的表现向你表示深刻的道歉
how deeply sorry I am for my earlier behavior
另外我很尊重并且钦佩你的领导
and how much I respect and admire your leadership.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以正如你所见
So as you can see,
你现在不仅可以储存你最喜欢的公式
not only can you store your favorite equations,
还能把他们转发给你的朋友们
but you can forward them to your friends
或是直接通过应用程序把他们贴到Facebook上
or post them on Facebook right from the app.
我真得说  这太厉害了
Well, I must say, I am impressed.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们显然为此花了不少心血
You all have clearly put in a lot of hard work.
的确如此
We have.
正因为这样  你们掌握了
As a result, you have taken
通往成功之路的最重要的一步
the most important step on the road to success:
在失败中学习
learning what not to do.
现在让我们重新开始吧
Now, let's start fresh.
霍华德  给我们弄点茶喝
Howard, we're going to need some tea.
好的  这双是雪地靴
Okay, these are Uggs.
这双是卡骆驰
These are Crocs.
这双是山寨版的马诺洛·布兰尼克
These are knockoff Manolo Blahniks.
无聊
Bored.
这可是你自己说的  我们要先建立一个数据库
Look, you said it yourself, we have to create a database
然后你才能写那个什么计算的东西
before you can write an alga-thingy.
是算法
Algorithm.
佩妮  阿兰图灵将算法定义为
You see, Penny, Alan Turing defined an algorithm...
英国数学家  逻辑学家  被称为人工智能之父
无聊
Bored.
好的
Okay.
这双是史蒂夫·马登
These are Steve Maddens.
这双是玖熙
These are Nine West.
这双是塔吉特  不过看起来很像香奈儿吧
These are Target. Oh, but don't they look like Chanel?
这双是迈克·科尔斯
These are Michael Kors...
*无人知晓*
Nobody knows...
*我曾经历的离乱*
the trouble I've seen
*无人知晓*
Nobody knows...
*我的悲伤*
my sorrows